Preliminary Guide to the American Economic and Tax Reform Pamphlets and Ephemera, 1919-1984 RL.01276
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
American Economic and Tax Reform Pamphlets and Ephemera
1919-1984
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.01276
2 Linear Feet
This is a collection of pro-Libertarian literature, which includes a wide range of conservative viewpoints. Accession (2009-0196) (1000 items; 2.0 lin. ft.; dated 1919-1984) consists of pamphlets, newsletters, newspapers, brochures, and other publications and periodicals from a variety of pro-libertarian and right wing organizations, including the American Economic Foundation and the National Economic Council, Inc. Topics include free market capitalism, price stabilization, the elimination or reduction of taxes, anti-communism, the Federal Reserve, inflation and the gold standard, the Marshall Plan, and foreign aid.
1000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The American Economic and Tax Reform Pamphlets and Ephemera were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2009.
Historical Note
Materials in this collection are from a variety of creators, but all deal with right-wing economic, pro-libertarian subjects.
Collection Overview
Accession (2009-0196) (1000 items; 2.0 lin. ft.; dated 1919-1984) consists of pamphlets, newsletters, newspapers, brochures, and other publications and periodicals from a variety of pro-libertarian and right wing organizations, including the American Economic Foundation and the National Economic Council, Inc. There is a wide range of materials, but many are related to topics such as gold and silver, the value of money, conspiracy theories, the taxation of the American people, and inflation. Early materials idealize the work of Henry George, a political economist who proposed a land value tax. Post-World War II materials frequently discuss foreign aid and the Marshall Plan, tending to espouse anti-communist viewpoints. 1970s-era materials tend to discuss gold, inflation, and monetary reform.
Libertarian literature; Propaganda, Anti-communist; Excessive profits tax; Price regulation; Free enterprise; Income tax; American Economic Foundation; National Economic Council, Inc.; Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (U.S.); Marshall Plan
- Accession (2009-0196), 2 boxes and 1 oversize folder
  Arrangement note
  Materials have been arranged by date. Newspapers were separated into their own oversize folder.
  - 1919-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950-1957 (Box 1)
  - 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Myths and Truths about Free Enterprise, 1958-1961 (Box 1)
  - 1960-1964 (Box 1)
  - 1965-1969 (Box 1)
  - 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - 1974-1976 (Box 2)
  - 1977-1984 (Box 2)
  - Society for Individual Liberty, approximately 1970s (undated) (Box 2)
  - Undated (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Newspaper articles, 1941-1956 (Oversize-folder 1)